# Teague Stockwell

Seattle, WA

Portfolio | GitHub | LinkedIn

# SUMMARY

Software engineer and transitioning service member with 4 years of experience in the US Air Force. Demonstrated proficiency and ownership of the full software development lifecycle to solve complex business problem like aircraft cargo loading. A passionate and consistent full stack developer that is quick to adapt and master the latest technology.

# **SKILLS**

**Languages** Typescript, JavaScript, Dart, Java

**Frontend** React, React Query, State Mgmt libs, HTML, CSS, Flutter, Android

**Backend** Next, Prisma(ORM), Express, Node

Services PostgreSQL, Firebase, Vercel, AWS(RDS, S3, EC2), Nginx Workflow CI / CD, Docker, TDD, GitHub, GitLab, Git, JWT, Jira

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Rainier Spark Tron | Lead Software Engineer

JBLM, WA | June 2021 - Present

- Deployed aircraft cargo management app to user base of over 2k that reduced weight and balance times 93%
- · Pioneered agile software innovation cell by mentoring new developers to promote diversity and inclusion

#### Aloha Spark Tron | Software Engineer

**Remote | Nov 2020 – June 2021** 

- Implemented 120 user stories while maintaining 2 CI pipelines with a total of 34 stages
- Leveraged CI/CD and DevOps to accredit and deploy a production app in < 5 months to a secure government cloud
- Wrote Mocha, Jest, React Testing Lib and Cypress tests for 2 services to increase line coverage to 80%

# **US Air Force | Aerospace Mechanic**

JBLM, WA | Oct 2017 - Oct 2020

• Lead & perform repairs / inspections on 20 assigned C-17 aircraft valued at \$3.2B

# **PROJECTS**

# Buildable – Social Media Platform | Code | Live App

PostgreSQL | Next | React | Node | AWS (S3, CloudFront, RDS), OAuth 2.0

- · Created post interaction with subreddits, threaded comments, likes, saves, rich text editing and mentions
- · Implemented a serverless REST API to manage pre signed image uploads and user roles

#### Levels V3 – Aircraft Cargo Loading | UI Code | API Code | Demo

PostgreSQL | Express | React | Node | Node | Docker

- · Created a React UI that subscribes to server updates and caches them to enable offline persistence
- · Developed an API for JWT based user roles and to sync pending updates between clients in near real time

#### Five Level V2 – Aircraft Cargo Loading | UI Code | API Code | Live App

Firebase | Express | Node | Flutter | Docker

- · Modified Docker imgs to create a CI /CD Pipeline for static code analysis, linting and testing to harden app security
- · Fetched data from a NoSQL Document DB (Firebase) and displayed a cargo loading UI with offline persistence

# **EDUCATION**

Southwestern College | B.S. Computer Programming Community College of the Air Force | A.A.S. Aviation Maintenance Aug 2019 – May 2021 Oct 2017 – Aug 2019